I started out, you know,
你知道,
as a young man in California going to,
作为California的一个年轻人,
I guess, local history museums about the history of the little town in California that I was raised in.
我从小在当地关于California一个小镇的历史博物馆长大.
I always liked them.
我一直很喜欢那些博物馆
Oh, I've been going to museums all my life.
Oh, 我这辈子常去博物馆.
I was brought up to do those kinds of things, you know,
我从小就习惯做那些事了, 你知道吗,
listen to opera at home, go to museums,
在家听歌剧, 去博物馆,
it was all part of my upbringing.
这都是我成长的一部分.
I think it's just a break from the every day,
我认为这是脱离日常生活的某种休憩,
the madness of the streets and people in your face all the time;
让人摆脱每时每刻都在你眼前晃来晃去的喧闹的街道和人群;
and it's very quiet in there,
那里非常安静,
and taking a little time to think about things other than the daily routine.
使人能花点儿时间想想日常琐事以外的事情.
I go to all kinds of museums.
我参观各式各样的博物馆.
I go to the museum of fine arts regularly,
我定期去艺术博物馆,
and I go to like to go to the small, funky museums
也去简朴的小博物馆
and I like to go and see special exhibits and I go all the time.
而且我喜欢去看特别的展览而且我总是去.
You go to see,
你去看,
er, different ways people express themselves,
er,人们表达自己的不同方式,
whether it's sculpture, folk art, or science, or, um, you know, fine art painting, or, or, whatever.
无论是雕塑, 民间艺术, 或是科学, 或是, um, 你知道的, 绘画, 或者, 或者, 诸如此类的东西.
It gets me in touch a little bit with I think what it means to be human, by looking at great achievements of past humans and human civilizations,
我觉得观看过去的人类和文明的伟大成就使我多少感受到作为人类意味着什么.
which I enjoy a lot,
这是我非常喜欢的.
it shows things to aspire towards I think often times and something to,
我常常想它展示了某种值得追求的东西，
I think if we understand these things,
我想如果我们理解了这些东西,
we can understand the present a lot better.
我们就能更好地理解现实.
I'm happier when I'm in a museum than any place in the world that I can think of.
在博物馆里, 我比在世界上任何我能想到的地方都更快乐.
But it's also like reading a book for me
但这对于我也像是在读一本书
I guess it's a quick way to learn new information.
我想这是一条了解新信息的捷径.